Inventory of the American Institutes for Research reports
Hoover Institution Archives
- General Topics File
  - 22500. Early growth planning study for Project LSEE (Box 25)
    - Interim report #5: The identification of critical variables for the early growth planning study, 1970 December
    - Interim report #6: The development of test and questionnaire items for the early growth planning study, 1971 August
    - Interim report #7: Early growth planning study listing of the source of information for each variable for which items were developed, 1971 October
    - Interim report #8: The design of tests and questionnaires for the early growth planning study, 1971 October
  - 22600. Further examination of exemplary programs for educating disadvantaged children
    - Progress reports (bound together)
    - Final report, 1971 July
  - 23100. Interim circuit order control system personnel subsystem test and evaluation
    - Phase 1 TST report, 1970 September
    - Appendices for Phase I TST report, 1970 September
    - Phase 1 final report, 1971 February
    - Phase 2 TST report, 1971 March
  - 24000. Effects of task index variations on training effectiveness criteria (Box 26)
    - Technical report, 1972 October
  - 24100. Mental health and retardation information and referral system: Requirements study
    - Final report, 1971 July
  - 24400. Development of a program for personnel subsystem test in BISP
    - Progress reports (bound together)
    - Position package test session guide (revised draft), 1973 November
  - 24700. Selected functional components of a vocational education counseling system for urban youth
    - Final report, 1971 November
  - 24800. Development of a supplemental training program for advanced salesmen
    - Phase 1 final report, 1972 April
  - 25000. Evaluation of Project SEED: A conceptually-oriented mathematics program for elementary school students
    - Final report, 1971 October
  - 25100. Evaluation of a science assembly program
    - Final report, 1971 August
  - 25300. TIRKS position test (Box 27)
    - Final report, 1971 August
  - 25400. Experimental assessment of an incentive program to enhance school learning: A pilot study
    - Final report, 1971 July
  - 25800. Allegheny County, Turtle Creek Valley model cities labor force, Phase II study
    - Final report, 1972 June
  - 26400. Psychobiological factors associated with monotony tolerance
    - Final report, 1972 July
  - 26500. Project TALENT
    - Technical progress reports #2, 4-9, 1971-1973
    - Project TALENT News, Vol. 10, No. 1, 1973 June
  - 26600. Preliminary proposal for an evaluation of two computer-assisted instructional systems
    - Interim report, 1971 August
  - 27000. Information seeking with multiple sources of conflicting and unreliable information
    - Final report, 1971 September
  - 27400. ESEA Title I: A reanalysis and synthesis of evaluation data from fiscal year 1965 through 1970
    - Informal progress report #1: An analytical review of the knowledge gained in five years of ESEA Title I about the education of disadvantaged children
    - Final report, 1972 March
  - 27700. A study of the operational feasibility of the apprenticeship work-study program for multi-site tryout and evaluation
    - Progress reports #1, 2 (bound together)
    - Final report, 1972 March
  - 27800. Development of an apprenticeship work-study program model for the cross-training of physical scientists for work in educational research and development (Box 28)
    - Progress reports (bound together)
    - Final report, 1972 February
  - 27900. The occupational health nurse and employee mental health: An evaluation study
    - Final report, 1973 November
  - 28401. Evaluation of the neighborhood educational center project in the Detroit public schools: A report of the fourth year's activities
    - Final report, 1972 September
  - 28404. Right to read
    - Final report, 1972 September
  - 28500. Feasibility of guidance, counseling, and pupil personnel services in employer-based career education
    - Interim progress report: Feasibility of individualizing education in employer-based career education, 1971 October
    - Interim progress report: Feasibility of guidance, counseling, and pupil personnel services in employer-based career education, 1971 October
    - Final report, 1972 June
  - 28600. Individualization of education in career education
    - Final report, 1972 June
  - 28800. Evaluation report of student support program - Minneapolis public schools
    - Final report, 1972 July
  - 30300. Changing schedules of work: Patterns and implications (Box 29)
    - Final report, 1973 February
  - 30500. Evaluation of Project SEED: A conceptually-oriented mathematics program for elementary school students
    - Final report, 1972 December
  - 30801. Improving reading comprehension: measuring readability
    - Technical report #1: New techniques for measuring and improving reading comprehension, 1973 February
    - Final report, 1974 May
  - 31200. The investigation of shelter management and control in natural disaster
    - Final report, 1972 December
  - 31400. Effects of task index variations on transfer of training criteria
    - Technical report, 1973 August
  - 31900. Exploration of the generality of self-image materials across ethnic groups
    - Final report, 1972 November
  - 32200. Navy career motivation programs in an all-volunteer condition: I. A cognitive map of career motivation
    - Technical report, 1973 March
  - 32400. Selected functional components of a vocational education counseling system for urban youth
    - Final report, 1972 September
  - 32500. The use of incentives to enhance school learning
    - Final report, 1972 November
  - 32700. An introduction to financial management for Navy managers: Final evaluation report
    - Final report, 1973 July
  - 32900. The implications of a "see-saw" model of organizational effectiveness (Box 30)
    - Final report, 1973 December
  - 33300. The development of revised field evaluation forms for educational research and development proposals
    - Final report, 1973 June
  - 33700. A program for research on human performance
    - Final report, 1973 June
  - 33900. Career education curriculum development: Grades K-9
    - Measuring dispositions toward the implementation of career education in the classroom
    - Progress reports (bound together)
    - Technical report #2, 1973 June
    - Papers on a career education curriculum. Technical report #3, 1973 July
    - Final report, 1974 October
  - 34500. Educational evaluation of the Optacon (Optical-to-Tactile Converter) as a reading aid to blind elementary and secondary students
    - Progress reports (bound together)
    - Interim technical report, Phase I, 1973 September
    - Final report, 1974 September
  - 34600. Planning, structuring, and evaluating practical career guidance for integration by non-college-bound youths
    - Practical career guidance for the non-college-bound student: A review of the literature
    - Case studies in practical career guidance. Reports #1-13, 1973 June (Box 31)
    - Final report, 1973 June
  - 34900. Project PLACE: A program of health career education
    - Final report, 1977 June
  - 35000. Careers in science: A Project TALENT study
    - Final report, 1975 October
  - 36100. Title VIII. Student support program: Minneapolis public schools
    - Evaluation report, 1972-1973
    - Interim evaluation report, 1973 February
    - Final report, 1973 July
  - 36600. Objectives, evaluation data, and case studies of the Temple City (California) differentiated staffing program
    - Report, 1972-1973
    - Final report, 1973 July
  - 37500. Development of a procedure to validate physical tests, 1974 July
  - 38300. A comparison of officer job content modules with activity groupings implicit in course design (Box 32)
    - Final report, 1973 August
    - The design of a system of job analysis for duty positions that infantry and quartermaster officers fill. Technical report, 1973 December
  - 38400. Results of field survey to evaluate an experimental set of officer duty modules
    - Groupings of similar positions by officer duty module applications and time (CODAP analysis)
    - Technical final report, 1974 January
    - Supplemental technical report, 1974 February
  - 38700. The televote system for civic communication: First demonstration and evaluation
    - Progress reports (bound together)
    - Final report, 1974 September
  - 39000. Technical support services for the Michigan Department of Education
    - Development of objective-referenced test instruments for social studies, grades 4 and 7 and metric measurement, grades 3-4, 6-7, 9-10
    - Development and validation of objective-referenced test instruments for entry-level first-grade children. Interim reports, 1974 August; 1975 June
    - Final report, 1976 December
  - 39100. Evaluation of the effectiveness of training devices
    - Literature review and preliminary model. First interim report, 1974 March
    - Evaluation plan for preliminary model. Second interim report, 1974 April
    - Elaboration and application of the predictive model. Third interim report, 1974 July
    - Evaluation of three burst-on-target trainers. Fourth interim report, 1975 February
  - 39500. Quality of life as perceived by 30 year old Army veterans (Box 33)
    - Progress reports (bound together)
    - Final report, 1974 November
    - Supplementary report, 1974 November
  - 39600. Evaluation of an ink print reading aid for the blind: The stereotoner
    - Progress reports (bound together)
    - Final report, 1975 December
  - 40400. Development of interactive dialogue modules that would provide junior officers with information about Army career planning policies, procedures, and strategies
    - Technical final report, 1973 December
  - 40700. Selected functional components of a vocational education counseling system for urban youth: A three year evaluation study, 1973 November
  - 40900. Students as teaching resources
    - Final report, 1973 October
  - 41600. Evaluation of the impact of the film series One to Grow On on selected teachers and students
    - Final report, 1975 June
  - 41700. The effects of question type and question placement on problem solving ability from prose material
    - Final report, 1974 January
  - 41800. Going metric: An analysis of experiences in five nations and their implications for U.S. educational planning
    - Final report, 1974 February; 2 copies
  - 43300. Development of a ROTC/Army career commitment model (Box 34)
    - First year technical report, 1974 November
    - Final report, Volume I, 1975 November; 2 copies
    - Final report, Volume II (appendices), 1975 November
    - Development of a career commitment model
      - Third and Fifth Quarterly Progress Reports
    - ROTC-program determinants of cadets' career commitment, 1976 July
    - Subgroup differences in ROTC/Army career commitment and in commitment-related attitudes, 1976 July
  - 43800. Allocating resources: Priorities in mental health services delivery
    - Innovations: Volume 1, No. 1 through Vol. 2, No. 2
    - Interim report (multiple copies), 1975 June
  - 44000. Methodology of the Project TALENT 11-year follow-up study (Box 35)
    - Progress reports
    - Final report, 1976 December
  - 44080. The American citizen: 11 years after high school, 1975 June
  - 44300. Design and validation of additional duty modules for engineer and ordnance officer positions
    - Final technical report, 1975 February
  - 44501. Replacing jobs with task clusters as the work unit for test validation
    - Final report, 1975 September
  - 45300. Project management needs and project management training: A review of the AID experience in Africa
    - Final report, 1974 November
  - 46800. Transfer training and skill retention
    - Final report, 1975 July
  - 47200. The impact of participant training on the attainment of development goals
    - Report No. 1: The study in Korea, 1975 November
    - Report No. 2: The study in the Philippines, 1975 November
    - Report No. 3: The study in Brazil, 1975 November
    - Report No. 4: Analysis of two sectors, 1976 March
    - Report No. 5: Final report: The methods and procedures for assessment of impact, 1976 March
  - 47500. A validated program development model and staff development prototype for comprehensive career guidance, counseling, placement, and followup
    - Final report, 1976 January
  - 47600. Technical report of a conference on career decision making
    - Technical report, 1973 May
  - 47900. Acceptability surveys of CCEM curriculum units (Box 36)
    - Interim report, 1974 November
    - Dialogue with publishers concerning publication of revised CCEM career education units.
      - Interim report, 1975 June
    - Field test and data analysis plan and summary status report. Interim report, 1975 September
    - Field test report: 130 career education modules, Part I. Final report, 1976 December
    - Field test report: 130 career education modules, Part II. Final report, 1976 December
  - 48000. Metric in service teacher training: Learning from the English and Australian experience
    - Descriptions of selected metric teacher training programs underway in the United States
      - Final report supplement, 1975
    - Teacher training in the metric system: An overview of selected programs in the U.S.
      - Final report supplement, 1975
    - Progress reports (bound together), 1975
    - Final report, 1975; 2 copies.
  - 48100. The vocational education curriculum specialist project
    - Vocational education curriculum specialist (VECS) Modules 1 through 9
    - Final report, 1977 January
  - 48200. Development of scientific careers: The high school years (Box 37)
    - Final report, 1976 August
  - 48300. The identification and description of exemplary bilingual education programs
    - Final report, 1975 August
  - 48900. Critical requirements for safe-effective nursing practice, 1976
  - 50200. Prototype job analyses of three supervisory positions within the New York City school system
    - Final report, 1975 June
    - Appendix A: Incident collection forms
    - Appendix B: Job inventory checklist procedures...
    - Appendix C: Reports of community school district visits...
    - Appendix D: Judgments of minimally accepted standards
    - Appendix E: Job inventory checklist response data
  - 50300. Competency training for non-degreed professionals in alcoholism (Box 38)
    - Interim report, 1975
    - Final report, 1977
  - 50600. Evaluating procedures for environmental sensing, orientation, and mobility by the blind, 2 copies.
    - Final report, 1976 February
  - 50700. Guide to the development, evaluation and use of criterion-referenced tests
    - Final report, 1976 August
  - 51100. You don't have to love each other but...: Final Report of the Boston Schools Pilot Project
    - Final report, 1975 July
  - 51200. Duty module methodology for officer career management system development
    - Final technical report, 1976 January
  - 52100. Career education in the public schools, 1974-1975: A national survey
    - Final report, 1976; 2 copies.
  - 52800. Improving the consumer protection function in post-secondary education (Box 39)
    - Consumer protection strategies: A literature review and synthesis
    - Study design and analysis plan. Technical report, 1975 October
    - Technical report 2, 1975 December
    - System for collecting, analyzing, and sharing information on institutional consumer protection practices: Regulatory user guide. Technical report 3, 1976 September
    - Final technical report, 1976 October
  - 52900. Health career databank for minorities/women
    - Final report: Longitudinal study of health careers from Project TALENT, 1976 May
    - Annotated selected bibliography, 1976 May
    - Design and feasibility study, 1976 June
  - 53100. Improving vocational education services for handicapped students
    - Final report, 1977 May
  - 53300. Vocational training and placement of the severely handicapped
    - Final report, 1977 June; 2 copies.
  - 53500. Identifying opportunities for improving the quality of life of older age groups
    - Final report, 1979 June
  - 53800. An audio digest system for communicating career education information
    - Final report, 1976 June
  - 54400. The link between learning disabilities and juvenile delinquency: Current theory and knowledge
    - Final report and executive summary, 1976 April
  - 54500. The current status of enlisted attrition in the U.S. Navy and in the U.S. Marine Corps and the search for remedies (Box 40)
    - Final report, 1975 November
  - 54800. Filipinos in the Navy: Service, interpersonal relations and cultural adaptation
    - Final report, 1977 January
  - 55300. Managing desegregation: A symposium of school desegregation in urban America, 1975
  - 55400. Project TALENT: A short history of a l-o-n-g project
    - Final report, 1977
    - Technical appendices, 1977
  - 55500. Impact evaluation for the project "Analysis and planning for improved distribution of nursing personnel and services"
    - Final report, 1976 August
  - 55600. Childbearing patterns, psychological traits, and the welfare of married couples, 2 copies.
    - Final report
  - 55900. Contraceptive attitude dimensions and the prediction of contraceptive behavior, 2 copies. (Box 41)
    - Final report
  - 56100. A study of special programs for children with specific learning disabilities, 2 copies.
    - Final report, 1976 December
    - Appendix to the final report: Case studies, 1976 December; 2 copies.
  - 56700. Evaluation of Wiche's regional program for nursing research development
    - Final report, 1977 September; 2 copies.
  - 58000. UDIS: Deinstitutionalizing the chronic juvenile offender
    - Executive summary, 1978 January
    - Final report, 1978 January
  - 58500. An information processing approach to performance assessment (Box 42)
    - Final report, 1978 November
  - 58800. Evaluation needs assessment for LEAA's evaluation development program
    - Final report, 1976 October
  - 59300. Evaluation of project information package dissemination and implementation
    - Interim report, 1978 April
  - 59500. Research and development strategy on employment-related problems of older workers
    - Final report, 1978 February
  - 59700. Consequences of adolescent childbearing for the young parent's future personal and professional life
    - Final report, 1977 June
  - 59900. Development and implementation of a national metric education technical support program
    - Final performance report, 1977 December
  - 60200. Development of a preparatory reading program for visually handicapped children
    - PREP: Preparatory reading program for visually handicapped children. Units VI-X
    - Final report, 1978 July
  - 60800. Overcoming barriers to mainstreaming: A problem-solving approach
    - Final report, 1978 July
  - 60900. Antecedents and consequences of the motivation for fertility control: A cross-cultural study of Filipino migrants and Caucasian controls
    - Final report, 1977 November
  - 61001. Process evaluation of selected WEEAP projects (Box 43)
    - Executive summary, 1980 January
    - Final report, 1980 January
  - 61700. Title I, 1965-1975: A synthesis of the findings of federal studies
    - Final report I
    - Controversies in the evaluation of compensatory education. Final report II
    - Summaries of major Title I evaluations, 1966-1976. Final report III
      These three reports dated July 1977.
  - 63500. UYA measurement and analysis requirements: Evaluation, 1978
    - Interim report, 1978 April
    - Strategy handbook for volunteer supervisors, 1978 September
  - 63600. Jobs for older workers in U.S. industry: Possibilities and prospects
    - Final report, 1977 September
  - 64400. Review of past educational projects in Liberia and recommendations concerning conduct of future EHR projects
    - Final report, 1977 February
  - 64700. Test revision recommendations for academic upgrading in the northwest territories
    - Final report, 1977 March
  - 65000. Developing consultation and education services for sexual assault
    - Final report, 1978 May
  - 65100. Final report on a study of the feasibility of the development of a standard system for describing job tasks
    - Final report, 1977 August
  - 65500. The Canadian experience: Implications for metric conversion in education (Box 44)
    - Executive summary, 1978 June
    - Final report, 1978 June
  - 66900. Mainstreaming workshops for vocational administrators
    - Final report, 1979 September
  - 67400. The implementation of a national metric education technical support program
    - Final performance report, 1978 December
  - 69000. An evaluation of the Arkansas project for the deinstitutionalization of status offenders
    - Final report, 1979 February
  - 70000. Origins and career consequences of sex differences in high school mathematics achievement
    - Final report, 1979 July
  - 72300. Getting the most from program-oriented mental health consultation, 1978 January
  - 75001. Composing and reading: A multidisciplinary view of theory and research
  - 75101. Combatting sex, race, and handicap stereotyping in career choice (Box 45)
    - Final report, 1980 June
  - 75300. The identification and development of community-based approaches for meeting the social and emotional needs of youth and families in variant family configurations
    - Final report, 1980 February
  - 75501. The consequences of being an only child: An analysis of Project TALENT data
    - Final report, 1979 December
  - 75600. The personal meanings of voluntary and involuntary childlessness
    - Final report, 1981 March
  - 75701. The one-parent/one-child family: Social and psychological consequences
    - Final report, 1980 June
  - 76401. Field testing vocational education curriculum specialist materials
    - Study design and analysis plan, 1979 April
    - Written summary of workshop accomplishments, 1981 September
    - Final technical report, 1981 September
  - 76501. A longitudinal study of the Army officer career commitment process
    - Final report, 1979 November
  - 76901. Assessing the Year 1 effort: A process evaluation of linking institutional networks to community and kinship systems, 1979 December
  - 77201. Postponing retirement: Identifying workers who might defer labor force withdrawal
    - Socio-economic policies and programs for the elderly, 1979 May
    - Final report, 1979 May
  - 78602. The national evaluation of the PUSH for Excellence project
    - Technical Report 3: The program, the school and the students, 1981 April
  - 78801. Job analysis of General Motors apprentice trades (Box 46)
    - Final report, 1980 January
  - 79400. The handbook for arson prevention and control programs, 1980 December
  - 80201. State regulatory agency field test of the AIR institutional report form
    - Final report, 1980 November
  - 81001. Contraceptive decision-making in adolescent couples
    - Final report, 1981 October
  - 81904. Competency measurement in vocational education: A review of the state of the art, 1981 June
  - 85601. Evaluability assessment of the Women's Educational Equity Act program
    - Phase I Final Technical Report, 1980 December; 2 copies.
    - Appendices for the Phase I final technical report
    - Rapid feedback evaluation of the Women's Educational Equity Act program. Phase II Final Technical Report, December 1981
  - 87710. Evaluability assessment of the deaf-blind center and services program (Box 47)
    - Final report, 1982 September
  - 87715. A pilot study of the ED/OM performance management system
    - Final technical report, 1983 September
  - 88800. New insights to improve the quality of life at age 70
    - Final report, 1982 May